Thanos: [Looking out the large window we saw at the end of "Thor: Ragnarok".] I know what it's like to lose. To feel so desperately that you're right... yet to fail, nonetheless. [grabs Thor by the head.] It's frightening. Turns the legs to jelly. I ask you, to what end? Dread it. Run from it. Destiny arrives all the same. And now, it's here. Or should I say...I AM. [Thanos holds up his hand to reveal the Infinity Gauntlet, which already hosts the Power Stone.] 
Thanos: [to Loki] The Tesseract, or your brother's head. I assume you have a preference. 
Thanos: Your optimism is misplaced, Asgardian. 
Thanos: That was a mistake. [Thanos stabs Heimdall through the heart.] 
Thanos: There are two more Stones on Earth. Find them, my children, and bring them to me on Titan. 
Thanos: If you consider failure experience... 
Thanos: "Undying." You should choose your words more carefully. [Thanos tightens his hold around Loki's neck. He makes eye contact with Thor before he increases his force on Loki's neck.] 
Thanos: No resurrections this time. [Thanos teleports away with the Black Order.] 
Thanos: What's wrong, little one? 
Thanos: (Kneels down to Gamora) What's your name? 
Thanos: You're quite the fighter, Gamora. Come. Let me help you. (THANOS takes her hand and leads her to a pavilion, where he produces a small red-jeweled dagger) Look. Pretty, isn't it? Perfectly balanced. As all things should be. Too much to one side, or the other... Here. You try. 
Thanos: Concentrate. There! You've got it. [Cut to the present, aboard the GUARDIANS' ship.] 
Thanos: I thought you might be hungry. 
Thanos: So I've been told. Even so. I'd hoped you'd sit on it one day. 
Thanos: You told me that too. Every day. For almost twenty years. 
Thanos: I saved you. 
Thanos: Going to bed hungry. scrounging for scraps. Your planet was on the brink of collapse. I'm the one who stopped that. Do you know what's happened since then? The children born have known nothing but full bellies and clear skies. It's a paradise. 
Thanos: A small price to pay for salvation. 
Thanos: Little one, it's a simple calculus. This universe is finite, it's resources finite. If life is left unchecked, life will cease to exist. It needs correction. 
Thanos: I'm the only one who knows that. At least, I'm the only one with the will to act on it. For a time...you had that same will...as you fought by my side. Daughter. 
Thanos: And in doing so, made you the fiercest woman in the galaxy. That's why I trusted you to find the Soul Stone. 
Thanos: I am disappointed. But not because you didn't find it. But because you did. And you lied. [Cut to shot of a large metal door opening. Thanos and Gamora stand there as a set of inner doors made of interlacing metal slide away. Inside, we see that NEBULA is suspended horizontally in the air in the middle of the room.] 
Thanos: Some time ago, your sister snuck aboard this ship to kill me. 
Thanos: And very nearly succeded. So I brought her here. To talk. (Thanos curls in both the power and space stones, causing Nebula's already extended pieces to stretch further outward. 
Thanos: (To Gamora) You're strong. Me. You're generous. Me. But I never taught you to lie. That's why you're so bad at it. Where is the Soul Stone? 
Thanos: Show me. [Cut to the pod where Thor, Rocket and Groot are.] 
Thanos: The stone had better be up there...For your sister's sake. 
Thanos: You know us? 
Thanos: Where's the Soul Stone? 
Thanos: I am prepared. 
Thanos: How is it you know this place so well? 
Thanos: What's this? 
Thanos: Tell me what it needs. 
Thanos: Of what? 
Thanos: (Turning to face Gamora with tears in his eyes) No. 
Thanos: I ignored my destiny once. I cannot do that again. Even for you. I'm sorry, little one. 
Thanos: I take it the Maw is dead. This day extracts a heavy toll. Still, he accomplished his mission. 
Thanos: And where do you think he brought you? (Star-Lord is near by behind wreckage with his weapon ready, and Spiderman is above the structure where Strange sits. 
Thanos: (Smiling reminiscently) It was. And it was beautiful. (Thanos uses the Reality Stone to show Strange Titan before it was destroyed) Titan was like most planets. Too many mouths, and not enough to go around. And when we faced extinction, I offered a solution. 
Thanos: But at random, dispassionate, fair to rich and poor alike. They called me a madman. And what I predicted came to pass. 
Thanos: I'm a survivor. 
Thanos: With all six stones, I could simply snap my fingers, and they would all cease to exist. I call that...Mercy. 
Thanos: I finally rest...And watch the sun rise on a grateful universe. The hardest choices require the strongest wills. 
Thanos: Ours? 
Thanos: Insect! (He then throws him, about to use the gauntlet, but is interrupted by an explosion caused by Iron Man shooting a missile at him. As the flames blind Thanos, Spiderman attaches a web to him, and strains against it. 
Thanos: It would've been a waste of parts! 
Thanos: ... My... Gamora...? 
Thanos: I... had... to. 
Thanos: You know us? 
Thanos: Where is the Soul Stone? 
Thanos: I am prepared. 
Thanos: How is it you know this place so well? 
Thanos: I saved you. 
Thanos: Going to bed hungry, scrounging for scraps? Your planet was on the brink of collapse. I was the one who stopped that. You know what's happened since then? The children born have known nothing but full bellies and clear skies. It's a paradise. 
Thanos: A small price to pay for salvation. 
Thanos: Little one, it's a simple calculus. This universe is finite, its resources ... finite. If life is left unchecked, life will cease to exist. It needs correcting. 
Thanos: I'm the only one who knows that. At least, I'm the only who the will to act on it. 
Thanos: [sheds a tear] No. 
Thanos: I ignored my destiny once. I cannot do that again. Even for you. [Gamora anguishly takes the double-edged knife Thanos had given her, then tries to kill herself. But Thanos uses the Reality Stone, turning the knife into bubbles] 
Thanos: I take it that Maw is dead? This day extracts a heavy toll. Still, he accomplished his mission. 
Thanos: Where do you think he brought you? 
Thanos: It was. [activates the Reality Stone, showing a holographic image of a populated Titan] And it was beautiful. Titan was like most planets; too many mouths, not enough to go around. And when we faced extinction, I offered a solution. 
Thanos: At random. Dispassionate, fair; To rich and poor alike. They called me a madman... and what I predicted came to pass. 
Thanos: I'm a survivor. 
Thanos: With all six stones, I could simply snap my fingers; They would all cease to exist. I call that... mercy. 
Thanos: I finally rest and watch the Sun rise on a grateful universe. The hardest choices require the strongest wills. 
Thanos: Ours? [Stark crushes Thanos with a pillar of wreckage] 
Thanos: The end is near. When I'm done, half of humanity will still exist. Perfectly balanced, as all things should be. [upon seeing Steve] 
Thanos: You should've... You.... You should've gone for the head!! [He raises his gauntlet and snaps his fingers] 
Thanos: Daughter? 
Thanos: Yes. 
Thanos: [solemly] ... Everything. [Now out of the Soul Stone, Thanos notices the damages inflicted on the scorched Gauntlet] 

